<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>memorandum7</title>
    <link>https://memorandum7.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on memorandum7</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 10:57:24 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://memorandum7.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mission Out Analysis</title>
      <link>https://memorandum7.com/posts/mission_out_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 10:57:24 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memorandum7.com/posts/mission_out_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: The views I express in these writings are my own and do not necessarily reflect the department, college, or university with which I am employed.
This post is the start to a series on my views pertaining to curriculum analysis, and my views on the process as it pertains to department-level review. But I must frame the following set of posts before I can proceed. While perhaps insufficient in its explanation, we will use the overview of &amp;ldquo;Curriculum&amp;rdquo; as preferred by Wiles &amp;amp; Bondi in their book &amp;ldquo;Curriculum Development: A Guide to Practive&amp;rdquo; which I believe shows the breadth of the field:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://memorandum7.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 10:16:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memorandum7.com/about/</guid>
      <description>About memorandum7 Chris Overly has a MAEd in Curriclum and Instruction and currently works as the Curriculum Manager for the Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering at the University of Washington. Previous experience in the construction industry and managing a metal fabrication shop creates a special lens for his view of instructional design and curricular systems.
This blog&amp;rsquo;s title, &amp;ldquo;memorandum7,&amp;rdquo; refers to Memorandum 7 at the University or Washington&amp;rsquo;s Graduate School:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introductions</title>
      <link>https://memorandum7.com/posts/introductions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 16:44:57 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memorandum7.com/posts/introductions/</guid>
      <description>Within higher education, the model of curriculum development by domain specialists, primarily faculty with knowledge in specialized fields that have no associations to the areas of pedagogy and educational leadership, we find an interesting dynamic on which specialized content takes the lead over instructional methods. At the same time, development of instructional methods is slowed by the faculty leadership&amp;rsquo;s lack of exposure to methods outside those used in their own education, leading to a slower improvement cycle within the departments and units where the curriculum in firmly under the purview of domain specialists.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
